# Pawan Saket

A-85, block A, Street no-7, New Ashok Nagar, New Delhi Delhi, Delhi, 110096 +91-7742923664 pawan\_saket@rediffmail.com

## Summary

Prolific, 2.8 years of experience and skills as a full stack JavaScript developer in modern core technologies with a passion of becoming best. Decreased rework by 20% by creating automation scripts and save time by 10%. Received promotion and collaboration on more projects and help to secure funds from the government by delivering a quality product in time with teamwork. Passionate about building world-class web applications and shaping the future.

#### Professional Skills

Reactjs, Redux, Webpack, Jest, Saas, Enzyme, AngularJS, Nodejs, Expressjs, HTML, CSS, GraphQL, MongoDB, Wordpress, Shopify, GIMP, Figma UI Prototype, Selenium WebDriver, Prometheus.

## **Employment History**

**Vuja De Labs** DL, Delhi

Engineer March 2017 - Present

- Build great interfaces using ReactJS, AngularJS, redux based on the material theme and bootstrap.
- Build backend logics on Nodejs, Graphql and MongoDB.
- Prototyped design for front-end.
- Decreased 20% rework and 10% cost by creating automation scripts.
- The best performer in quality analysis, promoted to head QA after 5 months of joining.
- Save time and cost by developing software to analyze company internet speed metrics using MEAN stack.
- Successfully Obfuscate code, Instance Monitoring, ease build process and E2E automation test cases developer.

**Topcoder**Remote, Oregon

Freelance Developer

August 2016 - January 2017

• Freelance crowdsourcing web project developer in javascript.

#### Zealand - Sjællands Erhvervsakademi

Roskilde

Intern Web Developer

August 2015 - January 2016

- Worked on an internship as a full-stack JavaScript Developer and created a social networking website.
- Learn and integrate with live projects and build real-time projects in the team.

# Vujade Design Projects

- 1. Data Karma based on ReactJS & GraphQL (click to visit)
  - Prototyped UI, developed frontend to backend code, structured the files, write test cases.
- 2. VigilantCS based on MEAN Stack (click to visit)
  - Developed pro version, contribute on the basic version, automate rework, Node Monitoring, code optimization.
- 3. Pellustro based on MEAN Stack (click to visit)
  - Improved existing UI, add modules, ease build process, automation test case, obfuscate code, QA.
- 2. Vujade Speed Test- (click to visit)

• My personal project contribution to the company for analysis of daily internet speed in the company.

### Personal Project

- 1. StickyPhoto (based on React + Redux) (click to visit)
  - Innovative project-based on ReactJS about the travel experience of the users, rating the experience and stick photo on remembering wall with others as a memory.

#### 2. Responsive Design

- Restaurant web design based on react, webpack (click to visit)
- Model agency web design based on react (click to visit)
- 4. Social networking site (based on MEAN Stack) (click to visit)
  - CollegetTalks is a social networking responsive website built on REST API and MEAN stack technology.
- 5. Video slot casino (javascript) (click to visit)
  - Video slot casino game based on the JavaScript technology and webpack.

### Achievements

- 1. Promoted as QA Head in vujade design
  - With the ability of no compromise on quality, the company promoted me as Head of QA.
- 2. NetEnt FrontEnd Developer Competition Winner (click to visit)
  - Secured First position for the interview from the competition held online by the NETENT.
- 3. Win a competition held all over the country for an internship in Denmark (click to visit)
  - Win a scholarship for the web development in Denmark by online examination all over Country in India.

#### Education

**Rajasthan Technical University** *Bachelor's Degree* 

Jaipur, Rajasthan Graduated July 2016